魔镜显示出什么?
What does the Mirror show you?
你看到了什么?
What do you see?
一个古老的童话故事,
An oft told tale.
关于白雪公主.
That of Snow White,
如何战胜巫后莱维娜,
how she vanquished the evil Queen Ravenna
夺回原本属于她的王位.
and took her rightful place on the throne.
然而还有一个故事, 一个不为人知的故事.
But there is another story, one you have not yet seen.
那是发生在"美满结局"之前的故事.
One that comes long before "happily ever after. "
就凭一个小卒?
A mere pawn?
一个小卒就足以颠覆整个王国.
A humble pawn can bring down kingdoms.
别让我分神.
Stop distracting me.
可怜的小卒仔.遇上了奸诈的国王.
Poor little pawn. Mean old king.
真是太可怜了.
So sad.
不过最后的生杀大权...
But the final say...
还是.
Well...
掌握在, 皇后手里.
Queen will have that.
皇后吃了国王.
Queen takes king.
你以为我说的 只是这盘棋吗.
And you thought this was just a game.
在魔镜的帮助下,
With the Mirror at her command,
莱维娜势不可挡.
Ravenna was invincible.
莱维娜攻破了一个又一个的王国.
She took her kingdom as she had taken others before it,
她的魔爪还会伸向下一个王国,
and as she would take others again,
而她的妹妹, 芙蕾雅, 始终陪伴在她身边
with her sister Freya at her side.
你爱上他了?
IS if love?
真的吗?
Truly?
是的, 我很爱他. 该你了.
It is love, truly. Your move.
我又何必多此一举? 赢的那个总是你.
Why should I bother? You always win.
是你总是让着我.
You always let me win.
对你我总是有千万个不忍心.
I suppose you are my weakness.
那好吧.
Very well.
皇后进五吃车. 三步之内将军.
Queen to rook five. Checkmate in three.
吸取教训, 芙蕾雅, 总有一天你会成功的.
Learn from loss, Freya, and your day will come.
一旦你内心的魔力得到释放
Your possibilities will be endless
你将会拥有无穷无尽的力量.
once the magic awakens in your heart.
不会的. 你我都很清楚. 我和你不同.
It won't. We both know it won't. I'm not like you.
我们家族的女人都是天赋异禀的, 芙蕾雅.
All the women of our blood are gifted, Freya.
总有一天...
And in time
你会挖掘出你自己的潜能, 就像我一样.
you will find the source of your power as I found mine.
或许吧.
We'll see.
怎么了?
What?
你怀了他的孩子.
You're carrying his child.
哦.
Oh.
你不知道吗.
You didn't know.
可惜.他已经和别人订婚了.
Well, he's promised to another.
可他并不爱她.
He does not love her.
他们的婚约既成事实 谁都无法阻止.
Their engagement is sealed. It cannot be broken.
他不会娶你的.
He will deny you.
他更不会承认你们的女儿.
And he will deny your daughter.
他不会这么做的.
He will not.
芙蕾雅.
Freya,
你别怪我残忍.
I'm not being cruel.
我只是单纯的想保护你.
I simply wish to protect you.
我会让你知道 一切并不会像你说的那样.
You may be surprised how things turn out.
你知道的很多, 莱维娜.
You know much, Ravenna.
但并不是所有的事情.
But you do not know all.
恐怕要让你失望了.
I'm afraid I do.
芙蕾雅并不相信他的姊姊.
Freya did not believe her sister,
因为爱情会让人变的盲目.
for love blinds even the clearest eye.
而就在她女儿诞生数月之际,
And when her daughter was but a few weeks old,
芙蕾雅的真心终于得到了回报.
Freya's trusting heart was rewarded at last.
她的心上人写了封信给她.
Her lover had sent word.
他选择违抗家族的意愿 和芙雷雅
He would defy his family and marry Freya in secret,
在御花园里秘密结婚.
in the Royal Garden.
他们会带着他们的孩子
They would gather their child
逃离这个王国 开始一段属于他们自己的生活.
and flee the kingdom to begin a life of their own.
芙蕾雅, 别过去.
Freya, don't!
我别无选择.
I had no choice.
我别无选择, 芙蕾雅.
I had no choice, Freya.
悲愤万分的芙蕾雅,
Consumed by grief and anger,
最终离开了她的姊姊.
Freya left her sister
前往遥远的北方 寻找属于她自己的国度
to seek a kingdom of her own in the land far to the north.
在那里, 人们无不害怕听到她的名字.
There, the people would come to fear her very name.
烧了! 杀光他们!
Burn it down! Kill them all!
失去孩子的芙雷雅,
For if she could not raise a child,
就在这里
then in its place
建立一支属于自己的军队.
she would raise an army.
老实点, 小子!
Come on, boy!
艾力!
Eric!
快跑!
Run!
给我过来
Come on.
芙蕾雅的到来 让原本翠绿的北方大地
Freya turned the once-green farmlands
变成了一片冰雪覆盖的荒芜世界.
of the north into a frozen wasteland.
他建造了自己的堡垒, 成为了冰雪女王.
There she built her fortress, and ruled as the Ice Queen.
放行!
Charrets!
你们多么的幸运.
How lucky you are.
有我在你们身边.
You're with me now.
你们就再也不会经历 这样的痛苦了.
And you will never know this suffering again.
你在害怕吗?
You are scared?
不.
No.
你是不是想念你的父亲?
Is it your father that you miss?
还是你的母亲?
Your mother?
- 是的. - 是吗.
- Yes.  - Yes.
你叫什么名字.
Tell me your name.
塔尔.
Tull.
所谓爱 就是个谎言.
Love is a lie.
它是残酷的人
It is a trick played by the cruel
用来玩弄愚者和弱者的手段.
on the foolish and the weak.
把它从脑海中抹去.
Cast it from your mind.
我绝不允许让爱扰乱你们的思绪, .
Never let it render you frail of mind
削弱你们的意志
or of will,
因为在我的王国 只有一条法则:
because in my kingdom, there is but one law.
"不准有爱."
"Do not love."
爱是种罪孽, 对此我绝不姑息.
It's a sin, and I'll not forgive it.
好了, 别再提什么家人和爱了.
Now, let's hear no more of family and love.
那些假象根本不值一提.
Those illusions are beneath you.
我会让你们摆脱爱的困扰.
I have freed you from them.
而对于这份恩赐. 我只要求你们回报我一件事,
And in exchange for this precious gift, I ask only one thing,
誓死效忠.
your loyalty.
你们将接受训练. 你们将变得强大.
You will train. You will harden.
你们将成为我的精英, 我的猎人军团.
You will become my elite, my Huntsmen.
从此你们将变得无坚不摧.
And nothing will ever, ever destroy you.
拿好!
Take it!
一. 二. 三.
One. Two. Three.
出棒!
Strike!
就这样, 孩子们渐渐成为了士兵.
And so children grew to be soldiers,
他们各个训练有素 骁勇善战.
becoming one with blade and arrow.
准备好弓箭!
Ready your bows!
拉弓!
Draw.
放箭!
Release!
侍卫.
Guard?
那男孩和女孩.他们是谁?
The boy and the girl, who are they?
叫什么名字?
What are their names?
哪两个?
Which?
最强的那两个.
The best ones.
艾力和莎拉, 女王陛下.
Eric and Sara, my queen.
我吓到你了吗?
Did I scare you?
难道你不知道吗?
Do you not know?
我从不失手.
I never miss.
放行!
Wagons!
新来了一批孩子, 长官.
The new children, sir.
时间差不多了.
It's about time.
到了, 孩子. 来吧, 动作快, 出来. 快点.
You're home, kids. Come on, hurry up.
下车吧 很好 快点.
Get out, come on. That's it.
来吧
Come on.
去吧孩子
Go, boy.
都出来!
Out!
来吧. 动起来, 快点.
Come on. Move, faster.
嘘
Psst.
你在那干嘛?
What you doing in there?
我知道这里的主人.
I know who lives here.
她太恐怖了.
She scares me.
好吧, 没错.
Ah, right.
有时她确实有点暴躁.
Yeah, she can be a wee bit grumpy from time to time.
你知道吗? 我不会让她猜透我在想什么.
Do you know what I do? I just never let her know what I'm thinking.
你是怎么做到的?
How do you do that?
好吧, 你做个凶恶的表情看看?
Well, can you make a mean face?
还不赖.
That's not bad.
像这样呢.
What about like this?
这次好多了, 战斗时你就这么做.
That's better. Now that's your war face.
当女王靠近时 你就做出这个表情,
If you wear that always when the queen is near,
她就不知道你在想什么了.
she'll never know what you're thinking either.
这样你就没事了.
You do that, and you'll be fine.
来吧.
Come on.
女王派她的军队.
The queen sent her army to wage war
征战北方列国
against the great kings of the north.
一场又一场的战争, 猎人军团战无不胜.
Battle after battle, they returned victorious.
可只有幸存者才能活着回来.
Those who were left alive.
你们做得很好, 我的孩子们.
You've done well, my children.
非常出色.
Very well.
你忘了走路绝不能出声.
You forget to walk in shadow.
而你也忘了稳住阵脚.
And you forget your balance.
这是在干嘛?
What are you doing?
看不出来吗, 你个傻小子?
You cannae tell, you daft boy?
我要嫁给你.
I'm marrying you.
这是我妈妈的.
It was my mother's.
是我唯一的宝贝.
My only treasure.
以前我为她而活.
I lived for her.
现在...
Now...
我要为你而活.
I live for you.
我们要怎么在这里相爱?
How do we live for each other in this place here?
芙蕾雅只要看我们一眼
Freya will take one look at us,
就知道, 什么事了?
and she'll know. And what then?
天一亮.
It's almost day.
拿上你的东西.
Gather your things.
到院子里等我.
Meet me in the courtyard.
他会抓到我们, 或者不会.
She'll catch us or she won't.
不论是哪条路..
But either way,
我们都会获得自由.
we shall be free.
你是爱我的, 对不对?
You do love me, don't you?
对, 我爱你.
Aye, I do.
我把我的生死都交给你.
I give you my life and my death.
无论生死, 我都不会离开你身边, 我向你发誓.
Stand or fall, I'll never leave your side, I swear it to you.
我听说过这个故事.
Yes, I know this story.
女孩总是偷偷的
The girl goes in secret
去见他的心上人.
to meet her one true love.
我很好奇 这次的结局又会是什么
I wonder how it ends this time.
你们俩所拥有的一切.
I gave you both everything.
到头来, 你们却背叛我.
And in return you betray me.
就为了爱.
For love.
我们替你争战沙场.
We fought your wars.
我们做得够多了.
We've done enough.
求您了, 女王, 放我们走吧.
Please, my queen, let us go.
别在我面前摇尾乞怜.
Do not beg me!
这是懦弱的表现.
It is weak.
你们太软弱了.
You are weak.
你们想离开是吧?
Do you want to leave?
非常好, 那就走到彼此身边.
Very well. Go to each other.
如果你们做到了
If you can.
我就答应放你们走.
And I'll let you go.
这应该不会太难.
Shouldn't be too hard.
因为爱能克服一切.
Love conquers all.
所以我听说过.
So I've heard.
别让我再看到他.
Take him out of my sight.
很久很久以前, 一对年轻男女陷入爱河.
Once upon a time a man and woman fell in love.
可惜好景不长.
But such things cannot last.
因为人心是如此地善变.
For the heart is a treacherous thing.
而爱情...
And love...
爱情只不过是一个童话故事而已.
Love is nothing more than a fairy tale.
日复一日 年复一年.
Days turned to years.
芙蕾雅的王国日益壮大.
Freya's empire continued to rise
与此同时, 猎人
while her sister Ravenna's fell
和白雪公主一举拿下了莱维娜.
at the hands of the Huntsman and Snow White.
可总有一股邪恶力量 萦绕着这个国度.
But some evil cannot truly be vanquished.
停下！
Halt!
谁在那里?
Who's there?
展示你自己!
Show yourself!
RAVE N NA; Kill...
杀了我.
Kill for me.
不要只是站在那儿,做点什么!
Don't just stand there, do something!
你疯了,老兄.
You're mad, man.
Aye, I wanted it an inch higher but the wind is tricky out here.
我们得到了什么?
What have we got?
那很精致
Well, that is exquisite.
哦.
Oops.
你没有权利.我有充分的权力
You have no right. I have every right.
这些是我的地盘
These are my woods.
这些都是女王的树林，我有一个皇家许可证.
These are the queen's woods. I have a royal permit.
也许是鹿,但不是小鹿
For deer, maybe, but not fawns.
小鹿 只有几周那么大
That one there was just a few weeks old.
我的你的营地,发现三个你杀的人
Like the three others you killed that I found at your camp.
它是美丽的你介意吗?  什么? 不.
It's beautiful. Do you mind? What? No.
放开我的马. 不,不,不
Release my horse. No,no,no.
我马上给钱
I'm keeping the horse as payment.
给钱是为了什么？
Payment for what? For the arrow.
它不喜欢他们在树上生长。
It's not like they grow on trees.
嗯，他们做的，但是没有尖点有
Well, technically they do, but not the pointy bit there.
那都是你的
That's all yours.
你将付款,平民
You will pay, commoner.
我会告诉女王,他将会知道
I shall tell the queen and the queen will have your head.
女王白雪公主吗? 是的.
Queen Snow White? Yes.
白雪公主
Snow White.
Hyah!
散开!
Fan out!
一字排开 !
Line the flanks!
再见了, 亲爱的.
See you later, love.
国王陛下
Your Majesty.
行了, 我的老友.
Please, my friend.
如果这是关于马的，我可以解释。
If this is about the horse, I can explain.
马 什么马
Horse? What horse?
没关系
Never mind.
你怎么找到我的?
How'd you find me?
花了不少功夫.
It wasn't easy.
莱恩.
Nion.
- 你答应过我的. - 对, 没错...
- You sworn.  - Yeah. Well, he...
可他威胁要把我扔进一个锅...一个大锅里.
he threatened to put me in a big pot.
胡扯. 她拿了我三块金币.
Nonsense. We paid him three gold.
三个? 就这么点?
Oh, three? Is that all?
每人三个.
Three each.
- 你又是谁? - 格里夫.
- Who are you?  - Gryff.
竭诚为您效劳.
At your service.
放债, 收钱, 都可以找我.
Bonds, rewards, debt collection.
- 我是他弟弟. - 他是, 半个弟弟.
- I'm his brother.  - He, half brother
同一个老妈
Same mum.
我们去那说.
Walk with me.
我有一件非常重要的事要拜托你.
I've come on a matter of grave importance.
是喔, 那你该找个同样重要的人来帮你.
You should find some gravely important people, then.
魔镜不见了.
The Mirror is gone.
本以为它的魔力会随着莱维娜的死而消失.
We believed its dark magic died with Ravenna.
可我们都错了.
We were wrong.
魔镜里有一股邪恶的
There is an evil within the Mirror
力量正在日益壮大.
that has only grown in power.
白雪她决定在这股力量失控之前
And Queen Snow White has vowed to rid her kingdom of it
让它彻底远离我们的王国.
before its darkness cannot be stopped.
两周前, 白雪她派了一队人马
Two weeks ago, the queen ordered a detachment of soldiers
将魔镜送往圣地
to take the Mirror to Sanctuary.
可之后他们就再也没有回来.
They never returned.
等等, 我不是你的手下.
Wait, wait. I'm not your man.
可你是我们王国中最出色的猎人.
You're the best tracker we have in the kingdom.
正如你说的, 魔镜是邪恶之物,
And as you say, the Mirror is evil
绝不能让它落入恶人之手.
and it mustn't fall into the hands of the wrong person.
那白雪以为就我能找的到魔镜吗?
And Snow White thinks I'm the one to find it?
是她授意你去找到魔镜的.
She commands you to find it.
然后把它送去圣地
And to deliver it to Sanctuary,
只有那样才能封存魔镜的邪恶力量.
where its wickedness can forever be contained.
你会帮我们的吧 不是吗?
Do you acceptor not?
当然, 当然, 当然. 他当然会啊.
Yes, yes, yes. He accepts.
何况到时候还有赏金.
Provided there's a reward.
我才不稀罕什么赏金.
I don't want no reward.
艾力.
Eric.
白雪她的情况不太好.
Snow White is unwell.
是魔镜...
The Mirror...
她说她会忍不住想看它.
She said she couldn't stop looking at it.
她还会听到魔镜的声音在召换她.
She could hear its voice calling for her.
所以她才要把魔镜送走.
That's why she sent it away.
那是什么东西?
What was that thing?
把你的全部兵力都转移到北面.
Move all your forces to the northern border.
为何? 你知道些什么?
Why? What do you know?
芙蕾雅, 北国女王.
Freya, Queen of the North.
那只猫头鹰是她派来的眼线.
That owl was her spy.
现在, 她已经知道魔镜的事了.
Now she knows about the Mirror.
如果让她得到了魔镜, 我们所珍视的一切都会变成冰雪.
And if she finds it, everything we hold dear will be covered in ice.
派人守住北境.
Move your men to the north.
你们还在这干嘛?
What are you two still doing here?
我们是你的搭挡.
We're your partners.
不, 我不需要搭挡.
No, you're not.
我也是白雪公主的人.
I am Snow White's man as well.
我是说-我是说小矮人. 如果需要帮忙, 算上我们俩!
I mean, dwarf. If she's in trouble, I wanna help!
女王陛下. 我们拿下了瓦尔达.
My queen, Vardhelm has fallen.
那是最后的要塞.
It was the last stronghold.
整个白色大地都是您的了.
The entire White Lands are yours.
您胜利了.
You've won.
我有吗?
Havel?
游戏还没结束.
The game's not finished.
这世界的尽头在哪? 更广的南方呢?
Is this where the world ends, or is there more?
女王陛下, 我们无法攻占南方.
My queen, the South cannot be conquered.
白雪公主的王国太大了, 而她的军队也...
Snow White's lands are too vast, her armies are too...
你早就知道艾力还活着?
Did you know that Eric was alive?
对不对?
Did you?
我...怎么会?
I...  How?
我向你发誓
I swear to you.
- 我亲手把他躯体... - 别紧张.
- I threw his body...  - That's alright.
这样反而更好.
I prefer it this way.
他在找一样东西.
There's something that he seeks.
而我想得到它.
I want it.
我姊姊的魔镜.
My sister's mirror.
它蕴含着巨大的魔力.
It holds great power.
有了它 我就能成就一番事业.
And with it at my command, I can do great things.
我会解救 每一个孩子.
I will free every child.
拯救他们所有人,
I will save them all.
就像当年的你一样
As I saved you.
而我的猎人军团会变得更强大
And my army of Huntsmen will grow
到时候 没人可以挡我的道
until nothing will stand in its path.
所以说, 游戏还没结束.
So, you see, the game is not finished.
让猎人军团待命.
Prepare the Huntsmen.
喔
Oh.
哦.猎人.
Oh. Huntsman.
嗯？
Hmm?
什么？有多少
What? How much further?
有多少
How much further?
什么？你说什么 让我找 我根本不知道
What? To the place I'm looking for that I don't know where it is?
这很难说
It's hard to say.
This one's had a strop on since we left.
他们是从这里走的.
They came through here.
再明显不过了.
Well, obviously.
这条是往北走的路.
This takes us to the northern road.
直接通往圣地
Leads direct to Sanctuary.
不是猎人也知道这些.
Don't need to be a Huntsman to know that.
嘿, 莱恩, 猜猜我是谁?
Hey, Nion, who am I?
哦
Ooh.
我在和尘土说话呢. 我听到它们和我说话了.
I'm talking to the dirt. I hear it speak to me.
他可是这方面的高手, 格里夫.
He's actually quite good at this, Gryff.
得了吧他. 他就是个小丑.
Get stuffed. He's a buffoon.
我们往北走.
Well... We ride north.
其实, 他们往西走了
Actually, they headed west.
往北走是一片平地 没有任何遮蔽物.
The northern road cuts through a plain. Nowhere to take cover.
往西走 旁边就是片森林.
The western road runs next to a forest.
他们会选择在那里扎营
That's where they would've made camp.
所以我们去那里找
That's where we're going to find them.
这很明显...
Obviously...
- 尘土又在和我说话了. - 它说了什么?
- The dirt is talking to me again.  - What's it saying?
他在说那个多嘴的傻瓜.
He's saying the mouthy one's an idiot
连自己的小命都保不住 不如早点卷舖盖回家.
who wouldn't last a day on his own, and should go home.
我很赞同.
I agree.
在拿到赏金之前我是不会回去的.
I'm not going home till I get my reward.
你不但拿不到赏金 还可能会丧命.
You want gold, but all you're going to find out here is death.
说得跟真的一样.
A bit dramatic.
对, 不过以防万一这是真的.
Dramatic, yeah, unless it's true,
我想我们最好考虑一下.
and then we should consider it an accurate warning, I think.
我才不怕什么芙蕾雅的冰雪.
I know I'm not afraid of Freya of the Frost.
嘿, 小声点. 说话别那么大声.
Oy. Not so loud. Keep your voice down.
你们比我想像中的还要愚蠢.
You're even more stupid than I thought.
哇。
Whoa.
真是见鬼.
Bloody hell.
谁会在光天化日下袭击他们?
Who would've attacked them out here in the open?
小心点. 他们可能还在附近.
Keep your eyes peeled. They could still be around.
找找看有没有他们的踪迹, 血迹, 或者其他的.
Look for tracks, blood trails Anything.
闪边去!
Go on! Get off!
都是他们自己的箭.
These are their own arrows,
他们自己的刀.
their own blades.
他们是互相残杀的.
They killed each other.
可为什么呢?
But why?
他们都是女王的手下.
These are all the queen's men.
魔镜当时就在这里.
The Mirror was here.
这绝不是他们自己的箭.
Well, this is definitely not one of theirs.
我从小在金矿里长大.
l grew up in the mines.
我敢说这东西价值连城.
That's worth half the world.
魔镜就在这东西的主人那里.
Whoever it belongs to has the Mirror.
我们得抢先在芙蕾雅之前找到.
We need to find it before Freya does.
这是什么?
What's this?
我们得往小路走.
We have to get off the road.
看他知道些什么
See if he knows something.
有点安静 你没事吧
Bit quiet. You all right?
小心 你没事吧
Fine. You all right?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm all right.
我想打听点... 消息.
I'm looking for information.
这么点钱打听不到什么.
You'll not get much for that.
我想问. 离这不远的地方发生过一场厮杀.
Well, there was a wee massacre on the road not far from here.
是女王的几个手下. 你知道这件事吗?
The queen's soldiers. You know anything about that?
没错, 几天前他们路过这里.
Yeah, they passed through here  a few days ago.
- 是吗? - 可他们没有停下.
- They did?  - They didn't stop. They weren't thirsty.
当时有人跟踪他们吗...?
Was anyone...  anyone following them or...?
哦, 给我也来一杯.
Oh, a pint as well.
看来是"不行"啦.
I take that as a "No""
再见.
Good day..
她以为她是谁啊.
A bit choosy for what she's offering.
或许你该找你的同类试试
Perhaps you'd have better luck with your own kind.
你见过女的小矮人吗?
Have you ever seen a female dwarf?
- 没, 我还真没见过. - 丑的惊世骇俗
No,I can% say I have. Horrifying.
惊世骇俗还算好的.
Horrifying's the best of them.
根本就是惨不忍睹.
Repulsive things.
丑如魔鬼的公牛
Ugly as the devil's bullocks.
所有的关节和头发
All knuckles and hair.
臭脾气和发育不良
Foul tempered and stunted.
不自然的，畸形的，金除根，满嘴脏话
Unnatural, misshapen, gold grubbing, foul-mouthed
成堆的侧向驴屁股
piles of sideways donkey ass.
我可真是孤陋寡闻了.
So, assuming this is a commonly held opinion,
那么小矮人宝宝都是怎么生出来的?
how exactly are new dwarves made?
呃, 一般来说都是意外.
Uh, generally by accident.
比如当时光线太暗.
Too little light.
- 或者酒喝太多. - 哈哈.
Too much of this. Yeah.
来吧, 干了它
Come on. Keep up.
门一开还真冷.
Chilly with that door open.
把那什么递给我.
Pass me the...
- 什么? - 有一些是我自己的.
What? Yeah, some of the...
看来你们三个都是远道而来.
You three look like you're far from home.
对, 没错. 进来避个雨 一会还要赶路.
Aye. Just taking shelter, then moving on.
他的太太一定很迷人.
The missus must be quite a looker.
真会说笑
That's a good one.
你刚才说什么?- 先搁一边.
What he say? That's all right.
不, 不, 不. 我可受不了.
No. No, I'm not having it. Aye.
你说话小心点, 可别闪掉舌头.
You ought to hold your tongue, mate, before you lose it.
不然是怎样?
ls that so?
如果就我一个人, 我根本就不担心
You know, if it was just me, I wouldn't be worried.
可加上他, 我就有那么一丁点担心了
If it was me and him, I'd be a tiny bit worried,
因为他实在太没用了. -
because he's a bit of a waster.
他胡说
Not true.
但这些都不重要  因为有他在这里.
But none of that matters, because we're with him.
眨眼的功夫, 他就能把你们的肠子掏出来
And he will gut you like a deer quicker than you can blink.
在你们面前这位...
Because this man here,
就是传说中的猎神.
this man is the Huntsman.
是真的吗?
Is this true?
你就是那个猎人?
Are you the Huntsman?
就是我. 好吧.
That's me. Well...
真是不巧...
The thing of it is...
我们都是猎人.
We're all Huntsmen.
我很抱歉... - 没关系.
I'm sorry. It's all right.
等等, 等等...
Wait, wait, wait.
有话我们好好说嘛?
Can we not talk about this?
你说自己是一名猎人?
You call yourself a Huntsman?
我还以为敢背叛女王的猎人有多厉害呢.
I expected more from a man who had the courage to betray his queen.
值得吗?
And for what?
就为了那个懦弱的女人
For the love of some spineless woman?
或许当年你还有几分能耐, 兄弟.
Maybe you were something in your day, brother,
可今时不同往日了
but that day is long gone.
准备好安心上路了吗?
Have you made your peace?
我很快, 就能安心了.
I'll have it soon enough.
告诉芙蕾雅 到死我都是自由的.
Tell Freya I died a free man.
芙蕾雅才不在乎你是怎么死的.
Freya doesn't care how you die.
没人在乎.
No one cares.
根本没人记得你.
You're already forgotten.
快撤! 大家快走!
LEIFR: Fall back! Fall back, now!
你老了不少.
You have aged.
莎拉. 莎拉?
Sara.
是我把你们绑起来的.
I tied you up.
她是他的妻子还是什么?
She his wife or something?
不, 不可能. 他的妻子早就死了
No. Can't be. His wife's dead.
死了?
Dead?
你是这么和别人说的吗?
Is that what you told everyone?
假装自己是一个伤心的鳏夫.
You poor, heartbroken widower.
这个故事一定让不少无知少女为你流泪吧.
That story must've wet the eyes of many a young lass.
甚至是以身相许.
Maybe more than their eyes.
不, 不, 不. 你已经死了
No, no... No, you're dead.
我亲眼看到的.
I saw you die.
这只是幻觉. 不可能是真的
This is not real. This is not happening.
你是鬼魂.
Or else I'm...
不然的话...难道...是我死了
Or else I'm dead.
我是不是已经死了?
Am I not alive?
你还没死.
You're alive.
你本来是该死了
Although, you should be dead.
你的头部被重击了六下...
You got hit on the head like, six...
你觉得是, 六还是七? - 七下
What do you think, six or seven? Seven.
对 七下 很严重.
Seven times. A lot.
所以, 这一切... - 千真...
So this is... Real.
万确
Very.
你以为我会忘了吗?
Did you think I'd forget?
你以为我会原谅这一切吗?
Did you think I'd forgive?
无论"生死", 你说过的
Stand or fall, you said.
你都不会离开我身边, 你说过的.
You'd never leave my side, you said.
你都发过誓的
You swore it.
而你却逃跑了
And then you fled.
我看着你战斗 我也看到你逃跑了
I see you fight, and I see you run.
不, 不, 不, 莎拉. 事情不是这样的
No, Sara. That's not what happened.
我当时看到的是塔尔杀了你
I saw Tull kill you.
我亲眼看到他杀了你. 否则我不会丢下你
I saw him kill you, with my own eyes. I would never leave you.
可我也是亲眼看见你离开
But I saw you leave me, with my own eyes.
而且所有人都知道
And you, of all people, should know
塔尔根本杀不了我
Tull could never kill me.
莎拉. 我...
Sara.
别说了. - 我向你发誓
Don't. I swear to you.
她把我关在地牢里
She put me in her dungeon.
整整七年了
For seven years.
当我最后逃出来的时候, 我发誓一定要找到你
And when I finally escaped, I swore I'd find you.
我花了不少时间
It's taken me a long time.
总算让我找到你了
But here we are.
所谓丈夫...
Husband
和妻子
and wife.
你真的相信这一切  相信我抛弃了你?
You honestly believe this? That I'd abandon you?
是的
Aye.
你还是忘了稳住阵脚.
You still forget your balance.
她还有一把刀
She's got another knife.
对, 没错. 我们应该早点说的
Yeah. Yeah, I probably should have said something.
Mmm-hmm.
她左边的靴子里还藏了两把匕首
She's got two more little ones in her left boot.
现在说也没用了
It's no longer important.
如果在我死前 还能多看你几眼
If your face is the last thing that I'm meant to see,
我死而无憾.
then I'm grateful.
既然这样 我就成全你
It should be the last thing you see.
哦
Oh!
我不喜欢她
I don't like her.
我一点也不喜欢她
I don't like her one little bit.
女王陛下
My queen.
别点火
No fire.
不准点火
No fire!
下去吧
It's all right.
那么.如果让芙蕾雅拿到了魔镜会怎么样?
So, what happens if Freya gets this mirror?
你不觉得我们之间
Don't you think that you and me
还有更重要的事可谈吗  比如我们
have other things to discuss, like us?
不
No.
到底会怎么样?
What happens?
她会变得势不可挡
She'd be unstoppable.
我的马在哪里?
Where's my horse?
我把它放了
I sent it off.
你放我的马做什么?
What did you do that for?
没有马就不会留下踪迹
No horses, no tracks.
我们不走大路, 避人耳目
We keep off the road, out of sight.
这么说, 你决定跟我走了?
So you're coming with me, then?
不, 是你跟着我走
No, you're coming with me.
好吧 你爱怎么说就怎么说吧
Yeah, whatever you need to tell yourself, that's fine.
在我看来, 要是没有我 你们会死得很惨
From what I can see, your wee band won't do too well without me.
什么? 不..
Huh? No...
不管魔镜蕴含了什么力量 我都不会让芙蕾雅得手的
SARA: Whatever power this mirror contains, I'll not let Freya wield it.
我们先找到魔镜 然后把它送去圣地
We'll find it, and we'll bring it to the Sanctuary.
等到一切结束后..
And then you and I
我们从此分道扬镳
will part forever.
现在.
Now.
告诉我这是什么
Tell me about this.
您是怎么想的？关于什么？
What do you think? About what?
你信任那个女人吗？
The woman. Do you trust her?
嗯 ， 我认为我们没有多少选择的余地
Well, I mean, I don't think we've got much of a choice.
除此之外,她就是个垃圾
Besides, she's pretty good in a scrap.
我想在很久以前就派上用场了
I imagine that would come in handy before too long.
天黑前就能到卡伦渡口了
We'll hit Callao Crossing by nightfall.
那里有黑市, 他们可能把魔镜给卖了
There's a market there. They might have sold the Mirror.
跟踪从来不是你的强项 对吗
Tracking never was one of your strengths, was it?
我不知道你在等待什么
I cannae wait to find out what yours is.
如果他们的箭都镶崁着钻石
If an enemy uses diamonds for arrows,
我不认为他们会把魔镜卖了换钱
I doubt they need to sell the Mirror for money.
那好,如果你不喜欢我的计划, 你可以别跟着我
Well, if you don't like my plan, you can piss off.
喔. 真是个万人迷
That is charming!
既然这样, 你也可以别跟着我
And you can piss off, too, as you so eloquently put it,
不过你别想摆脱我
but that's not gonna get rid of me.
你仍然是我妻子
You're still my wife.
我们...我们当时被骗了
Look, we were deceived.
那块冰是芙蕾雅的假象
The ice wall that Freya put between us,
她让我们看到她所制造的幻象
she showed us what she wanted us to see.
等等
Wait.
万一我是对的呢?
And what if I'm right?
难道不该给彼此一个机会吗?
Do we not deserve that chance?
这些都不重要了
It wouldn't matter.
你早晚还是会离开
You'd leave again.
我们的软弱让我们看不清真相
We blind ourselves to the truth because we're weak,
你说给彼此机会
because we hope.
我们之间已经没有机会了
But there's no hope for love.
爱情止于背叛
Love ends in betrayal.
这是不变的事实
Aye and always.
好吧, 我是不会放弃的
Well, I don't believe you.
别动. 别动
Don't move. Don't move.
喔
Ooh.
看来是老把戏了
That looks familiar.
小矮人就爱设陷阱. 我也经常那么做
Dwarf-made trap. It's where I would've put it.
没错. 要抓住我们可得换张大一点的网  才赶得上我们
Yes, it'll take more than that to catch the likes of...
喔, 不要啊
No! No!
好得不灵 坏的灵
Silly mope.
干嘛?
What?
我也没料到会这样
This was unexpected.
喔. 什么? 这么明显的陷阱还意想不到?
Oh, what? The hidden dwarf trap was unexpected?
你不是很利害的猎人. 你说呢
You're not the tracker you think you are.
因为有人让我分心了.
I've been a little distracted.
嘿, 多琳娜, 猎物上鈎了...
Hey, Doreena, we've got something.
大丰收. 大丰收.
Catch of the day, catch of the day.
上帝啊, 别这样
God, no.
小心点, 小帅哥
Careful, sweetheart.
我可不想毁了你那英俊的小脸蛋
I wouldn't want to ruin that pretty little face of yours.
好吧.
Okay.
喔, 饶了我
Oh, bugger me.
喔, 我们无冤无仇, 对吧?
Oh, it's like that, is it?
你甚至不认识我们
You don't even know us.
我为什么要认识你这个大饼脸的小矮人?
What do I need to know, you squat-faced little he-dwarves?
多看你一眼我都想吐.
Sight of you clots make me sick.
闭上你的臭嘴, 你个愚蠢的泼妇
Shut your mouth, you manky slag.
你才要给我闭嘴, 你个猥琐的家伙
Shut yours, you grotty wanker.
我去你的, 你这个丑八怪
Kiss my arse, you filthy minger.
我才去你的, 你这个天杀的浑球
Kiss mine, you wobbly shite box.
抱歉
Sorry.
小矮人女士 我们并不想冒犯你
Madam dwarf, we have no quarrel with you.
我们在找一面镜子
We seek a mirror.
可我这没有镜子
I don't got no mirror.
哈, 哈, 很明显啊
Oh, that's clear.
好啊. 喔, 你们欠揍...
Right. Oh, you are getting it.
不, 不, 不! 够了, 够了, 够了
No. No, enough,enough.
说说看你想要什么
Just tell us what you want.
嗯, 个人而言 我要你一丝不挂的 环绕在我身边
Personally, I'd like you to take your shirt off and prance around for me.
不过看你还算稳重的份上
But seeing as you're so modest,
我就劫个小财好了
I'll settle for every penny you've got.
啊, 原来你要的是钱啊
Aye, so it's money you're after.
我-我还真抱歉
MY apologies.
我身边只有这个
All I have is this.
你知道这是什么吗?
You know what this is?
这么大一颗钻石
It's a great big bloody diamond.
我又没瞎
I'm not blind.
你从哪弄来的?
Where'd you get that?
你放我们下来 我就告诉你
You let us down, and I'll tell you.
多琳娜!
Doreena!
马上来, 布朗温太太!
Coming, Mrs. Bromwyn!
替我看着这些家伙
Keep an eye on this lot.
如果他们俩再多嘴 你就放箭射他们
Shoot the he-dwarves if they get mouthy.
或你喜欢 随便射也行
Or if you just feel like it.
别摔着我们
You don't just cut it.
你口渴吗?
You thirsty?
我这有水 你要不要
I could get you some water, if you'd like.
哦. 好的, 谢谢你, 我都快渴死了
Oh, yeah. Thank you. I'd like that a lot.
啊. 我是说, 不  我才不稀罕你们的水
Ah! I mean, nah, I don't want nothing from the likes of you.
好了, 你们这些手下败将
All right, my little fishes.
要不要听听我的建议
I've got a little proposition for you.
合作? - 合作?
Truce? Truce?
除非先让我掐死你...
When I get my hands around your lice-bitten neck...
呀... 好了. 我们合作.
Yeah, yeah. He's just... Truce.
这颗钻石
Your diamond...
你是从一支金色的矛上取下来的, 对吧?
You got it from a golden spear, right?
是的, 没错
Aye, I did.
是地精
Goblins.
地精?
Goblins?
那不是一个愚蠢的传说吗
That old fishwives' tale.
你让我们相信这些?
You expect us to believe that?
我就看到了你这个又丑又蠢的家伙,
l expect you to stand there
所以安静的站在那别说话.
and look ugly and stupid, and say nothing else.
真的有地精.
Goblins is real.
世上最厉害的小偷.
Finest thieves in the world.
同时他们也贪婪成性.
And greedy as the day is long.
我们本来想抓一个的 - 没错.
We was trying to catch one. Yeah.
据说, 他们连盔甲都是金子做的
You know, they say their armor is made of gold.
在哪里能找到他们?
Where can we find them?
就在附近.
Not far.
在多利安河的上游有一片隐密的森林.
There's a hidden forest just up the Dorian River
就在圣地的西北面.
on the northwest side of the Sanctuary.
传说他们把所有的宝物都藏在那里.
They say they keep all their treasure there in that wood.
黄金, 白银, 珠宝, 一望无际.
Gold, silver, jewels, as far as the eye can see.
只要你的镜子够闪, 就一定会在那里.
If your mirror is shiny, it'll be in there somewhere.
我们可以从那里直通圣地?
Can we access the Sanctuary from there?
我不知道. 或许吧.
Dunno. Maybe.
那你们能带路吗?
ERIC: Will you show us the way?
好了, 你看, 所以我说我有个提议.
Ah. Well, you see, that's where the proposition comes in.
你要知道, 没人能活着走出那片森林.
You see, no one's ever come out of them woods alive.
你俩大个, 不过你们俩看起来倒像是猎人.
But you two big ones, you look like Huntsmen.
你们应该很有一套吧, 是吧?
And Huntsmen are pretty handy with a blade, yeah?
我们会和你们一起去
We all go in together.
你俩大个
You get your mirror.
你们应该很有一套吧, 是吧?
And me and Doreena fill our pockets
而我和多琳娜就负责填满我们的腰包.
with as much loot as we can carry.
成交?
Deal?
好, 成交.
Aye, deal.
走之前 让我先杀了这两个家伙. 什么? 不是吧.
Right after I kill those two. What? No.
怎么? 等等.
What? Hang on.
怎么?
Why?
我也不知道. 也许是有点喜欢他们吧.
I don't know. I like them, I guess.
为什么?
Oh.
喜欢小矮人, 你吗?
Like a dwarf, do you?
既然, 你是布朗温太太.
So, Mrs. Bromwyn.
那么布朗温先生在哪里?
Where's Mr. Bromwyn?
谢天谢地, 他死了.?
Dead, thank God.
他是怎么死的?
HOW did he die?
自挖双眼死的吗?
Gouging his own eyes out?
你再多嘴我就送你去问他.
Keep flapping your gob and you'll find out.
之前的事我很抱歉.
I'm sorry about before.
其实我当时很想喝水.
I would've drunk your water.
你刚才看上去有点口渴.
You seemed thirsty.
没错, 的确很口渴.
Yeah, I was.
我发现天热的时候. 我就容易口渴 还有跑步时也会.
I get thirsty sometimes if it's hot, or if I'm running.
- 我也是! - 嘿.
Me, too!
或者当我吃一些很咸的东西时.
Or sometimes if I eat something really salty, like, um...
- 就好比烤鸡. - 烤鸡.
Roast chicken. Chicken.
我知道你为什么不说话.
I know why you're not talking.
你说呢?
Do you?
因为你看到我和布朗温太太擦出火花了.
Aye. You noticed the sparks between me and Mrs. Bromwyn.
我也没办法, 她就是我的菜.
I don't know what to say. She's my type.
大嗓门 爆脾气.
Loud and angry?
嗯, 我过去就喜欢这样的, 不是吗?
Well, it's what I'm used it, isn't it?
那你们一定会过上幸福美满的生活.
I'm awfully sure you'll have a good life together.
没错, 我们会.
Aye, we would.
不过有个问题.
But there's a problem.
还有其他的女人.
Another woman.
个子高一点, 不过没那么漂亮.
Bit taller. Not as pretty, mind you.
听上去她不会蠢到在你身上浪费时间.
She sounds far too clever to waste her time with you.
可我怎么记得...
Well, I remember
刚才我还和她相拥在一张网上呢.
that one time we were caught up in a net together.
难道这是很久以前的事了.
This was a long, long time ago.
在你的故事里 你永远都是个英雄?
Are you not the hero of every story you tell?
没错, 那是因为我很勇敢.
That's because I'm very brave.
就像现在也是我保护你不被淹死.
Which is why I'm going to save you from drowning.
不然你想怎样...
And how do you expect...
这条船真是一不小心就会进水呢.
Some unpredictable waters around here.
不是我喔.
It's not me.
你真是活生生的傻大个.
You're a right galoot.
那你就是傻妞罗.
So are you.
我们到了.
We're here.
哦.
Oh...
哦, 亲爱的. 哦, 亲爱的. 来吧.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear. Come on.
你发现了什么?
What've you found?
打火石和铁块.
Flint and steel.
他们的血闻上去就像焦油.
Their blood smells like tar.
看到了吧. 都是金子做的.
You see? It is gold.
没错, 的确.
Yeah, it is.
是谁说没地精的 啊?
Goblins ain't real, eh?
快看.
Look.
小心别掉下去了.
Do your best to stay dry.
这真是太疯狂了.
This is bonkers.
你应该感谢至少这里还有一座吊桥.
Praise the bridge that carries you over.
RAVE N NA; Kill.
死尸.
Death.
又是自相残杀.
They killed each other.
就像女王的军队一样.
Just like the queen's army.
死尸.
Death.
现在怎么办?
What now?
去拿我们要的东西.
Now we take what we came for.
把它包起来. 千万别往里面看.
Keep it covered. Do not look into it.
快走开.
Bollocks.
去拿魔镜. 快!
The Mirror. Move!
- 这玩意真重. - 我什么都看不到.
This is heavy. I can't see anything.
哦, 你推到我了!
You're pushing me.
快走. 我看不见路.
Come on. I can't see.
别在乎你看见什么? 我看的见, 我在前面带路.
Cool it. You don't need to see. I can see. I'm at the front.
啊, 你踩到我了. 往右走.
Ah! Watch your feet. Move to the side.
抬好.
Lift.
哦, 我感觉到这桥在晃.
This bridge is wobbling!
我也知道桥在晃, 你能闭嘴吗?
it is obviously wobbling. Will you just shut up!
刚才看见没?
See that? Whoo.
我一直都带在身边.
I've never taken it off.
快跑吧, 亲爱的.
It's time to go, love.
跑, 跑, 跑!
Go, go, go!
把魔镜送到圣地去.
Take the Mirror to the Sanctuary.
快点.
Come on.
不
No.
快帮我点火!
l need fire. Come on.
千万别失手了.
Don't you miss.
我从不失手.
I never miss.
他救了我们.
He saved us.
艾力.
Eric!
你哭了吗?
Are you crying?
真想快点把那面魔镜给送走.
Can't rid ourselves soon enough of that thing.
再走两小时就能到圣地的中心了.
Look, the heart of Sanctuary's only two hours away.
要我说 我们得连夜出发.
I say we move tonight.
对, 看起来今晚夜色不错. 不会太暗.
Aye, there'll be a strong moon. Plenty of light.
不.
No.
谁知道黑暗中会埋伏着什么.
Who knows what's lurking in the dark?
这我同意.
I agree.
省省吧. 还有谁会是我们的对手.
Get stuffed. There's nothing out there could take us.
嗯哼, 你说得很对. 在酒馆我就抓到过你们.
That's right. I took you. In the tavern.
我也抓到过你们.
I took you as well.
那就天亮再走吧.
In the morning, then.
晚安.
Good night.
等送完魔镜之后.  我们就会去小矮人矿场.
And after the Sanctuary, on to the dwarven mining town.
他们一定都会抢着买我的宝贝.
Jewel and gold merchants, all looking to buy.
到时候我和多琳娜就要发大财了.
Me and Doreena's gonna make an absolute killing.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
- 多琳娜去哪了? - 还有莱恩?
Where is Doreena? And Nion?
哇啊.
Well...
你快看看那边.
Would you look at that?
泼妇.
Harpy-
这种呢, 就叫做飞燕草.
This one is called delphinium.
治疗痔疮和牙疼都很有效.
It's good for piles and toothache.
这种又叫什么?
What's this one called? Uh...
这只是普通的花而已.
That's just a flower.
我觉得它很好看.
I think it's beautiful.
我觉得你也很好看.
I think you're beautiful.
- 我吗? - 对.
Me? Yeah.
不.
No.
如果你要我谢谢你, 我已经说过了.
If you're looking for gratitude, you have it.
仅此而已.
Nothing more.
我到底该怎么做?
What exactly am I supposed to do?
你以为这事你说了算吗.
You think it's about you.
不
No.
你该怎么选择.
What you should choose.
你该做什么决定.
What you should do.
而我就在这里等人来救我 而你救了我.
That I'm just waiting here for the man to pass a test.
所以
And you did.
我就得爱你是吗.
So now I have to love you.
可我做不到.
But I don't.
做选择的应该是我.
I choose for me.
而不是你.
Not you.
所以 别再缠着我了
So let me go.
我说过. 无论生死, 我都不会离开你.
I can't. Stand or fall, I'll never leave you.
别再缠着我了! 别再缠着我了.
Let me go! Let me go.
莎拉, 别这样.
Sara, stop it.
你爱的那个人已经死了.
The one you loved is dead.
我甚至不记得当年的自己是什么模样.
I don't even remember what it feels like to be her.
我们没有要求
We did not ask for our sins.
那不是我们想要的人生.
We did not ask for this life.
艾力, 我做了...
Eric, I've done
许多可怕的事情.
terrible things.
不可饶恕的事情.
Unforgivable things.
我知道.
I know.
我也是.
So have I.
或许我们两个都不值得原谅.
Maybe you and me are not worthy of forgiveness.
可那些都是过去的事了.
That's for someone else to judge.
至少我们现在应该在一起.
But we are worthy of each other.
艾力.
Eric...
杀...
Kill...
过来...
Come
靠过来...
closer...
Closer.
靠过来...
杀...
Kill...
没错
Yes.
给我杀.
Kill for me...
你怎么了?
What are you doing?
你是真心的吗?
Have you been true?
艾力.
Eric.
我的心在你那, 由始至终.
My heart is yours, it always has been.
可如果你不是认真的...
But if this is a game...
了结了它.
End it now.
你对我是真心的吗?
Have you been true?
猎人, 这是什么情况?
Huntsman, what is this?
勇敢点, 兄弟.
Stand tall, brother.
艾力.
Eric.
我的艾力.
My Eric.
你的女王非常想你.
Your queen has missed you.
你已经不是我的女王了, 芙蕾雅.
You're not my queen, Freya.
我永远都是你的女王.
But I'm forever your queen.
你说是吗, 莎拉?
Isn't that right, Sara?
要知道... 是你抛弃了她, 艾力.
You see, you abandoned her, Eric.
而, 不是我.
But not I.
是我让她从绝望中站起来.
I raised her from despair.
也是我让她变得 像现在这样无坚不摧.
Made her the point of my spear, my tempered steel.
她带领我的军队
She's laid waste to kingdoms
攻破了无数的王国. 让像你一样的男人俯首称臣
and brought men such as you to their knees.
她和你已经不一样了.
She's everything that you're not.
我只要让她回到你身边
All I had to do was send her to you,
你自然会带我们找到魔镜.
and you led her straight to the Mirror.
太可悲了.
It's pathetic.
哦, 这些又是什么?
Oh, what are these?
小矮人.
Dwarves.
他们看上去就像个孩子.
They're just like children.
我们可不像孩子那么好惹, 老巫婆.
We're mighty far from children, Bitch Queen.
很可爱.
Adorable.
把魔镜带回去.
Bring me the Mirror.
有本事先杀了我再说!
You'll have to kill me first!
不.我不杀你.
No, I won't.
不.多琳娜, 不要!
NION: Doreena, no!
你早就知道了. 对不对?
You knew, didn't you?
你知道她会背叛你 可你还是让她留下来.
You knew she'd betray you and you spared her still.
这次你吸取教训了吗?
Have you learnt my lesson at last?
继续伪装你的内心, 冰雪女王.
Harden your heart, Queen of Winter.
你甚至可以冰封整个世界.
Bury the world in a tomb of ice.
可没有用的.
It matters not.
爱还是会延续.
Love will endure.
或许你说的对.
Yes, perhaps you're right.
那就让我们来看看吧?
Shall we find out?
杀了他.
Kill him.
他死了吗?
Is he dead?
我想是的.
I think so.
那怎么办?
What do we do?
把箭拔出来.
Pull it out.
快啊!
Go on.
一. 二.
One, two...
利落点!
Quickly!
见鬼, 真是太疼了.
Bloody hell, that hurt.
没想到她居然射偏了!
I don't believe it! She missed!
她从不失手.
She never misses.
你是不是傻了?
Have you lost your mind?
她背叛了我们!
She betrayed us.
艾力, 她不是丘比特.
Eric, she is not Cupid.
我可不认为 你胸口的那一箭是她爱的表示.
I doubt that an arrow to the chest is an expression of her love.
喔, 不, 不.
No,no,no.
好戏才刚刚开始, 我的朋友们,
There is a grand design at work here, friends.
我已经感觉到了.
And it grows even louder.
头部受创. 第八次.
Head injury. Number eight.
她从不失手.
She never misses.
听着, 我比你们俩加起来都生气.
Look, lam twice as angry as you are.
多琳娜是我在世上唯一的朋友.
Doreena was the only friend I had in this world,
你得接受这个事实.
but you need to face facts.
莎拉她并没有站在你这边.
Sara is not on your side.
我不需要你相信我所相信的.
I don't need you to believe what I believe.
它们又是干嘛的?
What are these for, exactly?
让我给你点提示.
I'll give you a hint.
不是我们骑它就是它骑我们.
We're not gonna carry them on our backs.
你打算怎么做? 一路跟去北方?
So, what are you gonna do? Trek all the way to the frozen North?
赤手空拳对抗女巫和她的军队吗?
Face down an evil sorceress and her entire army?
差不多.
Aye.
好吧, 算上我!
All right, I'm in!
塔尔, 把小矮人放进画室 并把魔镜带到我的密室去.
Tull, put the dwarves in the gallery and bring the Mirror to my sanctum.
欢迎回来, 莎拉.
Welcome home, Sara.
芙蕾雅...
Freya.
到我这来...
Come to me.
念出来...
Say the words.
把它们念出来...
Speak the words.
"岁月是无情残酷的
"The age can be wicked
对于那些孤军奋战的人.
"to those who walk alone.
当我站在魔镜面前,
"When I look into the Mirror,
内心的真我才会慢慢浮现."
"I see myself as I might become."
没错...
Yes.
魔镜, 魔镜告诉我,
Mirror, Mirror on the wall,
谁才是这个世界上最美丽的人.
who is the fairest of them all?
不用躲开我.
Do not back away from me.
你刚才问的那个问题.
You asked a question.
魔镜回答你了.
The Mirror has answered.
莱维娜, 怎么会?
Ravenna, how?
你不是已经 死了吗?
Are you not dead?
是.
Yes.
也不是.
No.
介于两者之间.
Something in between.
你比以前更坦率了, 芙蕾雅.
You've become quite literal, Freya.
所有人中, 你应该最清楚.
Of all people, you should know
身体, 不过是一具躯壳.
that is but a vessel.
我离开了我的身体.
I left my body.
躲进了魔镜之中.
I went into the Mirror.
我一直在那里.
And there I stayed.
成为了魔镜的一部分.
I became part of it.
被困在里面.
Trapped.
直到你刚才释放了我.
Until you released me.
我们还有很多事要做, 我的好妹妹.
We have much to do, little sister.
只要有了你 以及你的军队.
With you and your army by my side,
我一定能收复我的王国.
I will regain my kingdom once more.
白雪公主
Snow White
我会让你跪在我的面前.
shall kneel before me.
她会求我饶恕她.
She will beg for mercy.
而我终将掏出她的那颗心.
And then I'll tear her heart out.
比我想像中大多了.
Oh, that's a bit bigger than I imagined.
我们的计划是?
So what's the plan?
我们有计划对吧?
You have got a plan?
对.
Aye.
那计划周全吗?
Is it any good?
不.
No.
不过很简单.
But it's simple.
芙蕾雅会在尖塔的密室里.
Freya will be in her sanctum, below the steeple.
我会想办法从上面爬上去, 进而杀了她.
I'll make my way down from the top, find her, and kill her.
那莱恩和多琳娜怎么办?
What about Nion and Doreena?
会有人进去帮我们找到他们的.
I've got someone on the inside who's gonna help me find them.
- 哦, 谁啊? - 你们.
Who? You.
你给我的猎人军团下了新的命令.
You have given my Huntsmen new orders.
更好的命令.
Better orders.
明天会有两组人同时出击.
We will attack tomorrow in two waves.
兵分两路进攻.
Flanking maneuver.
我相信你会同意的.
I presumed you would agree.
我的谋略更胜你一筹.
It's a far superior tactic.
这是我的王国!
This is my kingdom.
你刚才说什么?这是我的王国!
Did you say something? This is my kingdom!
当然是你的.
Of course it is.
这里永远都会是你的王国.
And it always will be.
我永远不会质疑我妹妹的统治权.
I would never question my sister's rule.
可是在这围墙外面,
But beyond these walls
就是我的王国.
is my kingdom.
我说了算.
My dominion.
你别忘了你欠我的一切.
Do not forget what you owe me.
是我成就了今天的你.
I made you what you are.
来吧. 往前走.
Come on. Move along. Faster.
快点 跟上.
Follow your brother.
向前走, 快跟上.
Look lively now.
你, 跟上. 动作快.
You as well. Go on.
靠拢
Shut it.
靠拢.愚蠢地人
Stop sniveling. Twerp.
别停下.
Keep walking.
千万别停下.
Just keep walking.
这件事不能怪我妹妹, 大人.
It's not my sister's fault, my lord.
小的时候她的脸被东西砸过, 一大块石头.
She was hit in the face as a baby with a rock.
你们俩, 跟我走.
You two, come with me.
- 你非得下那么重的手吗? - 闭嘴.
Did you have to hit him so hard? Shut up.
这家伙真沉.
He's very heavy.
好了. 把他塞进这里.
Right.
就没人会看到了.
We stuff him in here, we cover our tracks.
你这活干得真是太粗糙了, 就那样.
That's very sloppy work, that is.
这真是有史以来最蠢的计划.
This is the worst plan ever.
停下
Stop.
你不记得我了吗？
You don't remember me, do you?
不记得呀
No.
这是我的战争
This is my war face.
皮帕
Pippa.
我知道你为什么在这里
I know why you're here.
你真正的目标.
Aim true.
我的孩子们。
My children.
为了这一天的到来...
This is the day for which...
什么叫做害怕.
For which you were born.
你们将面对的敌人 他们从未输过一场战争.
You will face an army of men who have never lost a war,
是从未...
men who have...
他们忘记了...
Who have forgotten...
…什么是害怕
...what it means to be afraid.
而我们会让他们...
We will bring fear
再一次
once again
白雪公主的军队
to Snow White's army.
再次害怕... 白雪公主的军队
And their lands will be mine.
还有他们的王国, 而他们的孩子...
And their children...
他们的孩子...
Their children...
我是这里的女王.
For I am queen.
我是你们的女王.
lam queen.
为了今天我不断训练你们.
This is what I trained you for.
为了今天我栽培了你们.
This is why I raised you.
所以你们才能成为我的猎人军团.
This is why I made you what you are.
你好吗, 艾力.
Hello, Eric.
我可想死你了.
I've missed you.
侍卫!
Guard!
为什么?
Why?
因为他们相爱.
They're in love.
你闻不出臭味吗.
They reek of it.
这里难道不是你的王国吗?
Is this not your kingdom?
当然是.
It is.
那你没立下国法吗?
Do you not have laws?
我有.
I do.
那么...
Then what
该如何处置他们?
is your judgment?
死刑.
Death.
嗯
Mmm.
叛徒!
Traitors!
背叛了谁?
Traitors to who?
你们的老女王? 还是新女王?
Your old queen? Your new queen?
你触犯了法令
You broke the law.
法令吗?
The law?
你忘了那些爱你的人吗?
Have you forgotten the ones who loved you?
你们的母亲, 你们的父亲
Your mothers, your fathers.
他们也犯法了吗?
What law did they break?
爱并不会让你们软弱.
Love does not make you weak.
相反的它给我力量.
It's all that ever gave me strength.
塔尔 我们不曾并肩作战吗?
Tull, have we not fought side by side?
我们的孩提时代!
We were children!
兄弟姐妹, 难道不是彼此相爱吗?
Brothers and sisters. Did we not love each other?
和我一起战斗.
Fight with me.
即使死, 也是为了爱你的人.
If you die, you die for something that's yours.
你为什么不敢看我们, 芙蕾雅?
Why do you turn away, Freya?
当年你骗了我们, 现在又要骗你自己吗.
You deceived us, and now you deceive yourself.
给我安静
Silence.
当时为什么不杀了我们?
Why did you not kill us back then?
而是让我心死 让她恨透了我.
Instead, you break my heart and turn hers against me.
很漂亮.
Pretty.
看到了吗, 猎人.
You see, Huntsman,
爱情救不了你们的命.
love doesn't save your life.
我早就知道.
I should know.
因为我也死过一次.
I've been dead before.
对不起.
I'm sorry.
真的对不起.
I'm so sorry.
无论生死.
Stand or fall.
都要在一起.
Together.
- 我们并肩作战.
I stand with you. Aye.
- 对
Aye.
别动.
Don't.
往后退!
Stand back.
没人救得了你, 猎人.
Nothing can save you, Huntsman.
只会让你死的 更痛苦 !
All that's left is pain!
莱维娜, 快住手. 快停下!
Ravenna, stop. Stop!
我说够了 !
Enough!
我们不能把魔镜留在这里.
We can't leave the Mirror.
我们爬上去.
Then we climb.
我以为我已抹杀了你软弱的一面.
I thought I had driven the weakness out of you.
我以为我让你变得更强.
I thought I made you strong.
可你还是那么可悲 就像当年一样.
But you're as pathetic as you ever were.
你是不是疯了?
Have you lost your mind?
你是怎么让我变得更强的?
How did you make me strong?
又是怎么抹杀我软弱的一面?
How did you draw the weakness out?
你做了什么?
What did you do?
我没必要向你交代任何事.
I don't have to tell you anything.
哦. 哦, 可怕的是你做了.
Oh. Oh, but you do.
你看, 你自己也说了.
You see, you said it yourself,
你的存在介于这个世界和魔镜之间.
you're something between this world and the Mirror.
是我把你召换出来.
I summoned you out.
现在, 你得听从我的命令!
Now you are bound to me!
快告诉我真相.
Tell me the truth.
魔镜, 魔镜 告诉我
Mirror, Mirror on the wall...
谁才是这个世界上最美丽的人?
...who is the fairest of them all?
是你, 女王陛下.
You are, my queen.
可不久之后.
But not for long.
你的妹妹即将诞下一名婴儿.
Your sister holds a baby to her breast.
是个女娃.
A daughter.
当这个女娃长大之后 自然就会超越你的美丽了.
She will grow to be more beautiful than even you.
你不能要求我做这些事情.
You cannot ask such a thing of me.
这并不是我的要求.
I ask nothing.
我只不过是你内心的反射.
I am but a reflection.
而其实你...
And you...
你的内心早已做出决定.
You have already decided.
杀...
Kill.
给我杀...
Kill for me.
我是那么爱她.
Yeah, I loved her.
我是那么爱你.
I loved you.
所以我才会比你更强大!
That's why I'm stronger than you.
离我的孩子们远点!
Leave my children alone!
对不起.
I'm sorry.
我对不起你.
I'm sorry
我杀了你的女儿.
I killed your daughter
同时也释放出在你内心隐藏的力量.
and released the greatest power within you.
可你却把你强大的力量浪费在愚蠢的感情上!
A power you have wasted on nothing but cheap sentiment!
你以为我不想要孩子吗?
Did you not think I wanted a child?
你以为我不想得到爱吗?
Did you not think I wanted love?
不过这些东西...
But these things
... 对我并不重要.
were not meant for me.
因为我有更大的梦想!
I have a higher calling!
你依然相信...
Do you still believe
... 爱情能对抗一切吗?
that love conquers all?
即使不是一切.
Maybe not all.
至少是你.
Just you.
准备好了吗, 猎人?
Are you ready, Huntsman?
来啊.
Aye.
你们是多么的幸运.
How lucky you are.
来吧.
Come on.
呼吸. 哦, 呼吸.
Freed.
我没事呢.
I'm all right.
- 你没事吧? - 你也没事吧?
Are you all right? Are you all right?
- 没错. - 没错.
Yeah. Yeah.
你看, 是太阳!
Yeah! Hey look, the sun!
很久很久以前, 有一个美丽的女王,
Once upon a time there lived a beautiful queen
她的心碎成了两半.
whose heart was broken in two.
虽然被埋葬在冰雪之下...
But even buried under ice and snow,
但她的爱永续存在.
love survives.
- 这辈子你都别想. - 好吧. 好吧. 好吧.
Not on your life. Fine, fine.
你这么容易就放弃了吗?
You're gonna give up that easily?
天啊, 你真是蠢到家了.
God, you're stupid.
北方的冰雪渐渐融化.
The lands of the North were free
白雪公主的王国也避免了一场战争.
and Snow White's kingdom was safe from harm.
最后, 一些童话确实成真了.
And so, some fairy tales do come true.
而他们的故事 仍然继续.
But none ever truly end.